VICTOR FAJARDO

13297C Blueberry Ln #202, Fairfax, VA 22033 | (703) 4597611 | <u>fajardo.de.leon@gmail.com</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/victorfajardo</u> | <u>github.com/VictorFajardo</u> | <u>stackshare.io/victorfajardo</u>

Software Engineer

Full-Stack Software Engineer, Lead UI Developer and Mentor with over a decade working in advertising, currently looking for new directions and opportunities to continue growing professionally.

- **Willing to learn,** enthusiastic about job challenges, new technologies and self-learning to keep up to date with market trends.
- **Innovative software engineer** offering experience in the full software development lifecycle from concept through delivery of next-generation applications and customizable solutions.
- Proficient in advanced development methodologies, tools and processes contributing to the design and rollout of cutting-edge software applications.
- **Known for excellent troubleshooting skills** able to analyze code and engineer well-researched, cost-effective, and responsive solutions.
- **Experienced in team leadership,** offering an ideal balance of technical expertise and emotional intelligence while also keeping a focus on the big picture.

Skills

Methodologies: Agile | Scrum | Kanban | Waterfall | Incremental | UML

Development: OOP | MVC | MVVC | OOCSS

Languages: HTML5 / XHTML | CSS3 / SASS | JavaScript | TypeScript | PHP | Java | C++ | Python **Frameworks:** React | GatsbyJS | NextJS | Angular | AngularJS | Node | Express | Webpack |

Code Igniter | Django | WordPress | Drupal

APIs: REST APIs | Google APIs | Twitter API | Epsilon API | Brightcove API | Hubspot API |

Mailchimp API

Libraries: jQuery | Redux | GreenSock / GSAP | Bootstrap | Material Design | Lodash |

Foundation | TailwindCSS | Styled-Components | Scroll Magic | ThreeJS | Axios

Databases: MySQL | SQL | MongoDB | GraphiQL **Version Control:** Git | GitHub | GitBucket | SVN | CVS **Code Deployment:** AWS CodeDeploy / CodePipeline **Test-Driven Tools:** Jest | Cypress | Karma | Jasmine

Bug Tracking Tools: Jira | BugHerd

Debugging Tools: Firefox Developer Tools | Chrome Developer Tools | De MonsterDebugger

Servers: Apache | AWS EC2

Software: Adobe CC Suite: Photoshop / Illustrator / Animate / After Effect / XD | SketchUp |

Microsoft Office Suite | Postman | FileZilla | Bitvise

IDEs: Visual Studio Code | Atom | WebStorm | PhpStorm | Eclipse | Sublime

Spoken Languages: English | Spanish (Native)

Professional Experience

Senior Software Developer, Jun 1996 to Present – Freelancer, America/Europe

Worked over 2 decades in software development, using cutting edge technologies to create pixel perfect products for companies in South America, North America, and Europe, creating solutions for international brands like Coca-Cola, Nestlé, Beiersdorf, Nextel, Kimberly-Clark, among others.

Latest Projects:

Tweet Feed - https://github.com/VictorFajardo/tweet-feed
App to show tweets by popular search and filter them by hashtags. Architect designed and developed with Create React App / Redux Toolkit / Node / Express / Styled-Components / Axios / Lodash.

Software Engineer / Senior Lead UI Developer, Jul 2019 to Present – <u>WUNDERMAN THOMPSON</u>, Washington, DC

Lead developer and project architect designing, developing, testing, deploying, and maintaining several high traffic responsive websites, interactive experiences, rich media banners and user medical tools for pharmaceutical companies like Pfizer, Merck, Johnson & Johnson, Boehringer Ingelheim, Kaiser Permanente, among others. Delivered cutting-edge technology products using modern frameworks like React and Angular, with a pixel-perfect level of detail and commitment.

Achievement Highlights:

- Contributed software engineering expertise in the planning process of products and services through the software lifecycle, from requirements definition through successful deployment, actively participating in the decision-making process.
- Assumed the leadership and management of the development department as interim director after the departure of our former director.
- Assigned task and projects to developers based on their capabilities, experience, and growth path. Cultivated a one-to-one professional relationship with team members to encourage them to grow professionally.
- Participated in clients and vendors presentations due to ability to translate technical issues into easy-to-understand software solutions. Helped client service team to close deals and agreements with clients based on cost-benefit decision making.

Featured Projects:

- Pfizer Discovery Center https://www.pfizerdiscovery.com/
 Immersive experience for the Pfizer Discovery Center with interactive modules and 360°
 views. Architect designed and developed with Create React App / Redux /ThreeJS / Material Design / BootstrapJS / Brightcove API.
- Exploring Kaiser Permanent (approved staging link: http://q-kp.wdc-dev.com/)
 Immersive experience to explore Kaiser Permanente with interactive modules and animations. Architect designed and developed with Create React App / Redux / ThreeJS / Material Design / BootstrapJS.
- Boehringer Ingelheim MSL Doctor App (in internal staging state)
 Interactive touchscreen experience for doctors and health professionals to be used at

- medical conventions. Architect designed and developed with Create React App / Redux / BootstrapJS.
- Understanding ILD Progression https://www.lungsandyou.com/ild-progression/
 Interactive experience to explore the progression of the Idiopathic Lung Disease (ILD) on the human body. Designed in Angular with a custom animation engine developed integrally for the client requirements.
- Lungs & You® https://www.lungsandyou.com/
 Awareness web portal with multiples user medical tools and stunning animations. Architect designed and implemented in Code Igniter PHP / AngularJS / Angular / REST APIs / Google Maps API / Brightcove API.
- OFEV® https://www.ofev.com/
 Drug website with information about the product and support tools for caregivers and patients. Architect designed and implemented in Code Igniter PHP / AngularJS / REST APIs/ Brightcove API.
- Innovation.org https://www.innovation.org/
 Web portal to explore the innovative research and technological breakthroughs of America's biopharmaceutical industry, and get to know the people behind the fight to prevent, treat and cure disease. Developed in Drupal / ¡Query / BootstrapJS / YouTube API / Hubspot API

Senior Web Developer / Lead UI Developer, Dec 2016 to Jul 2019 – <u>WUNDERMAN THOMPSON</u>, Washington, DC

Achievement Highlights:

- Mentored entry and mid-level developers, preparing them to take an active participation of the development of the department projects. Trained new department members to integrate them to our development process.
- Facilitated customization of systems by encouraging development team to adopt high level standards for software application development, architecture, continuous deployment, innovative frameworks, modern IDEs, and tools.
- Interviewed candidates to the department based on the demands of the position and the incoming projects to be developed.

Web Developer, Nov 2014 to Dec 2016 – <u>WUNDERMAN THOMPSON</u>, Washington, DC *Achievement Highlights:*

- Introduced methodologies and best practices that enhanced product definition, release processes and customization of applications to client needs creating products of undemanding scalability and facile maintenance.
- Created quality standards for the development of banners and rich media banners that were later adopted by other branches of the company. Contributed with my experience in the process of conceptualization and brainstorming of banner campaigns.

Web Developer, Oct 2014 to Nov 2014 – <u>PRECISION STRATEGIES</u>, Washington, DC Developed HTML5/Flash banners as developer contractor.

Web Developer, Sep 2014 to Oct 2014 – <u>GRAFIK</u>, Alexandria, VA Developed HTML5/Flash banners as developer contractor.

Web Developer, Oct 2014 to Nov 2014 – <u>MARCOM GROUP</u>, Fairfax, DC Updated the Air Force Flash Multimedia Kiosk as developer contractor.

Production/Web Director, Nov 2009 to Apr 2011 – <u>PURPL.</u>, Nashville, TN Developed HTML5/Flash website as web development and production director.

Web Developer, Mar 2008 to Oct 2009 – <u>INQUBA AGENCIA INTERACTIVA</u>, Lima, Peru Developed HTML5/Flash websites, portals, and games as web developer.

Web Developer / Content Creator, Jun 1996 to Jul 2003 – <u>YUPI / CIUDAD FUTURA</u>, Miami, FL / Madrid, Spain

Developed content related to Video Games: Articles, News, Tools, and Guides, among others.

Education

2018 - NORTHERN VIRGINIA COMMUNITY COLLEGE – Annandale, VA
Computer Science | Associate of Science – AS
Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society

2004 - UNIVERSIDAD MAYOR DE SAN MARCOS – Lima, Peru **Electronic Engineering | Bachelor of Engineering – BE**